Oleg Razgulyaev

Team Leader at Rambler

oraz@mail.ru

Summary

Developer/Architect of highload web applications using machine learning or/and other AI methods. R&D.

Experience in bioinformatics (biophysics, molecular biology)

Specialties

Web, highload, machine learning, data mining

Main languages: C, C++

Prototyping/scripts/tests: perl, bash, octave

OS: FreeBSD, linux

SQL: mySQL

NoSQL: Berkeley DB, Redis

Algorithms: general, machine learning, Al

Experience

Team Leader at Rambler

January 2002 - Present (10 years 2 months)

- highload web advertising service with 10 millions visitors per day
- stable performance with 500 times traffic's growth from start up
- heavy realtime statistics subsystem for ads targeting on visitor behavior
- context adverising in search results subsystem
- targeting by visitor profile subsystem
- ads realtime auction subsystem
- geography and demography targeting subsystem

Senior Software Engineer at Stack Group

June 1999 - December 2001 (2 years 7 months)

- startup: advertising system from scratch (ads management, ads rotation, realtime statistics, wed interface)
- core of this advertising system works at Rambler so far

Senior Software Engineer at Institute of Protein Research

January 1990 - May 1999 (9 years 5 months)

- software for genome sequencing with nested strand hybridization
- development of systems of control devices

- interactive graphics systems under MS Windows
- graphics system under MS DOS

Postgraduate at Institute of Protein Research

March 1984 - November 1989 (5 years 9 months)

- investigation of the kinetics of protein folding
- experimentally proved the existence of an intermediate state in protein folding
- software program of decomposition of the kinetic curve
- study of the interdomain mobility of proteins

Skills & Expertise

Machine Learning

Artificial Intelligence

Web Development

SQL

Algorithms

(Intermediate, 5 years experience)

(Beginner, <1 year experience)

(Advanced, 14 years experience)

(Intermediate, 10 years experience)

(Intermediate, 10 years experience)

Matlab

(Beginner, <1 year experience)

Bioinformatics

(Intermediate, 10 years experience)

(Intermediate, 5 years experience)

Unix

(Intermediate, 14 years experience)

Perl

(Intermediate, 5 years experience)

Bash (Intermediate, 5 years experience)
C (Expert, 20+ years experience)

C++
Online Advertising
(Expert, 14 years experience)
Statistics
(Advanced, 14 years experience)
Data Mining
(Intermediate, 5 years experience)

Information Retrieval (Intermediate, 5 years experience)
Simulation

Neural Networks
Anomaly Detection
Biophysics (Intermediate, 5 years experience)

Molecular Biology (Intermediate, 5 years experience)

Linux

Courses

Stanford online courses

Introduction to Artificial Intelligence, by Sebastian CS221

Thrun and Peter Norvig, Stanford

Machine Learning, by Andrew Ng, Stanford CS229A

Academic Earth

Introduction to Computer Science I, by David J. CS50 Malan, Harvard
Death (Introduction to Philosophy), by Shelly
Kagan, Yale
Introduction to Psychology, by Paul Bloom, Yale

Publications

OLEG RAZGULYAEV, ANATOLY RUBINOV, MIKHAIL GELFAND, and ALEXANDER CHETVERIN. Sequencing Potential of Nested Strand Hybridization

Journal of Computational Biology. Summer 1995, 2(2): 383-395. 1995

Authors: Oleg Razgulyaev

Semisotnov G.V., Rodionova N.A., Razgulyaev O.I., Uversky V.N., Gripas' A.F., and Gilmanshin R.I. (1991) Study of the "molten globule" intermediate state in protein folding by a hydrophobic fluorescent probe.

Biopolymers 31, 119-128 1991

Authors: Oleg Razgulyaev

Michael A. SINEV, Oleg I. RAZGULYAEV, Maria VAS, Alexander A. TIMCHENKO and Oleg B. PTITSYN Correlation between enzyme activity and hinge-bending domain displacement in 3-phosphoglycerate kinase

Eur. J. Biochem. 180,61-66 (1989) 1989

Authors: Oleg Razgulyaev

O.B. Ptitsyn, R.H. Pain, , G.V. Semisotnov, E. Zerovnik, O.I. Razgulyaev Evidence for a molten globule state as a general intermediate in protein folding

FEBS Letters 1990

Authors: Oleg Razgulyaev

Semisotnov GV, Vas M, Chemeris VV, Kashparova NJ, Kotova NV, Razgulyaev OI, Sinev MA. Refolding kinetics of pig muscle and yeast 3-phosphoglycerate kinases and of their proteolytic fragments.

Eur J Biochem. 1991 Dec 18;202(3):1083-9. 1991

Authors: Oleg Razgulyaev

Semisotnov GV, Uversky VN, Sokolovsky IV, Gutin AM, Razgulyaev OI, Rodionova NA. Two slow stages in refolding of bovine carbonic anhydrase B are due to proline isomerization.

J Mol Biol. 1990 Jun 5;213(3):561-8. 1990

Authors: Oleg Razgulyaev

Education

Stanford online courses

2011 - 2012

Academic Earth

2008 - 2010

Sankt Petersburg State University

MS, Biophysics, 1978 - 1984

Oleg Razgulyaev

Team Leader at Rambler

oraz@mail.ru



Contact Oleg on LinkedIn